<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-26T20:27:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Walden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/2022/12/26/walden.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Walden" /><published>2022-12-26T20:24:51-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-26T20:24:51-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/2022/12/26/walden</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/2022/12/26/walden.html"><![CDATA[<p>Currently reading.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="books" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently reading.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Walden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/26/walden.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Walden" /><published>2022-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/26/walden</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/26/walden.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I went to Walden Pond. It’s a bit of a famous body of water here in Massachusetts as it was home to Henry David Thoreau for over two years (2 years, 2 months, and 2 days, to be exact). He actually lived in a little cabin on land owned by Ralph Waldo Emerson who allowed Thoreau to conduct his experiment there.</p>

<p>At Walden Pond is where he wrote down his thoughts about life, which were compiled into a book of the same name. I bought that book today in search for words to attach to my feelings of wandering.</p>

<p>I walked along the edge of the pond, all the way around. It was clear and crisp with fresh winter air - the kind of air that makes for a good night’s sleep.</p>

<p>I skipped rocks.</p>

<p>I broke icicles into little pieces.</p>

<p>I listened to my footsteps on the forest floor, hearing how the pitch changes depending upon if I focus on my left foot first or my right.</p>

<p>I wondered whether I could live so simply.</p>

<p>Is this for me?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I went to Walden Pond. It’s a bit of a famous body of water here in Massachusetts as it was home to Henry David Thoreau for over two years (2 years, 2 months, and 2 days, to be exact). He actually lived in a little cabin on land owned by Ralph Waldo Emerson who allowed Thoreau to conduct his experiment there.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This Is Living</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/25/this-is-living.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Is Living" /><published>2022-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/25/this-is-living</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/25/this-is-living.html"><![CDATA[<p>I just spent the last two nights in a<a href="https://getaway.house/">Getaway</a>. The ethos of the entire experience is to disconnect, embrace nature, yourself, and find a new balance.</p>

<p>I’ll be making a lengthier version tomorrow since I want to keep this short tonight.</p>

<p>But I feel like I’ve experienced something primal. Something that braced me by my shoulders, shook me, and said “Hey, wake up. This is living.”</p>

<p>I now want to figure out how to feel that everyday.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just spent the last two nights in aGetaway. The ethos of the entire experience is to disconnect, embrace nature, yourself, and find a new balance.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Disconnected</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/24/disconnected.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Disconnected" /><published>2022-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/24/disconnected</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/24/disconnected.html"><![CDATA[<p>Disconnected in a<a href="https://getaway.house/">Getaway</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disconnected in aGetaway.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back To Simplicity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/23/back-to-simplicity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back To Simplicity" /><published>2022-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/23/back-to-simplicity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/23/back-to-simplicity.html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, there seems to be a growing energy around bring simplicity back to the web. For instance, just today, on the top of HN, were two posts about RSS feeds and bringing them back.<a href="#0">[0]</a><a href="#1">[1]</a></p>

<p>I’ve also seen a growing number of blog posts from<a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bearblog</a>which, had I not already made this blog, I’d happily use its interface (I’m actually considering transitioning, but haven’t pulled the trigger just yet). It’s “bear” bones. Just text. No fluff. It isn’t trying to use data. <strong><em>It respects you as a user</em></strong>.</p>

<p>I found this is the case for a growing number of companies. They’re focusing on being the antithesis of what’s currently seen in big tech. They thrive off being the ones that don’t track you, don’t try to scam you, and really just represent good business. One of my favorites, and one that I use on my projects, is<a href="https://plausible.io">Plausible</a>. They make analytics simple with a position starkly opposed to how Google does it. They respect their users. Add a script to your site and you’re done. It’s private, so no need for GDPR banners or anything. It’s fantastic and it just works.</p>

<p>This trend of returning to the roots of the internet, towards the simplicity, doesn’t feel like it’s going backwards - it feels as though we’ve learned lessons along the way and have become more appreciative of the pureness of the simpler aspects of the web.</p>

<hr />

<p>[0]<a name="0"></a> <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34105572">This is the year of the RSS reader</a></p>

<p>[1]<a name="1"></a>  <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34105558">It’s time for an RSS revival</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, there seems to be a growing energy around bring simplicity back to the web. For instance, just today, on the top of HN, were two posts about RSS feeds and bringing them back.[0][1]]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Balance And Fulfillment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/22/balance-and-fulfillment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Balance And Fulfillment" /><published>2022-12-22T08:53:06-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-22T08:53:06-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/22/balance-and-fulfillment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/22/balance-and-fulfillment.html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had a discussion about work and life. One of us was arguing that work and life is a balance. The other thought that it was not a zero-sum game, but rather the goal is for both to be fulfilling.</p>

<p>And it got me thinking, is there a way to combine these two schools of thought? Can work and life both be a balance <em>and</em> be a non-zero-sum game?</p>

<p>Let’s imagine that I’m able to work exactly 8 hours per day, live life 8 hours per day, and sleep 8 hours per day. Just based on time alone, this appears “balanced”. It is, by the traditional definition, a “good work/life balance”.</p>

<p>In equation form, the day looks like this:</p>

<center>t_work + t_life + t_sleep = 24</center>
<p>where t_work = t_life = t_sleep = 8.</p>

<p>But it is rarely a reflection of how the day <strong><em>feels</em></strong>. What if we change the equation a bit, get a bit relativistic, and add in some “time dilation” constants (disclaimer: not actually relativity, but just roll with it, eh?). These constants will provide a better representation of how time feels, even if the raw hours themselves might be equal.</p>

<p>Here’s the new equation:</p>
<center>c_work * t_work + c_life * t_life + c_sleep * t_sleep = 24</center>
<p>where c_i &gt;= 0.</p>

<p>Let’s take a hypothetical day and see what happens. This day was a rough one. There were multiple deadlines that were due, presentations throughout the day, maybe a code review. All of this whiplash makes it seem as though the day just won’t end. The c_work in this case is large, let’s say 1.5. So, if I actually worked for 8 hours, it felt like 12.</p>

<p>So, 12 out of the 24 hours are already gone.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently had a discussion about work and life. One of us was arguing that work and life is a balance. The other thought that it was not a zero-sum game, but rather the goal is for both to be fulfilling.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Car Sounds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/22/car-sounds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Car Sounds" /><published>2022-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/22/car-sounds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/22/car-sounds.html"><![CDATA[<p>Some days are good. Some days are bad. Some days are in between.</p>

<p>But on all days, I like to lay in bed and listen to the sounds of cars passing by.</p>

<p>Whoosh.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some days are good. Some days are bad. Some days are in between.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Indiecompjobs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/12/21/indiecompjobs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indiecompjobs" /><published>2022-12-21T13:00:49-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-21T13:00:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/12/21/indiecompjobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/12/21/indiecompjobs.html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea came from me looking for a job myself. I became disenchanted by all the VC-backed companies. Instead, what if there was a way to find private companies, that are profitable and looking to grow. None of that magical, profitability-will-come-later business.</p>

<p>I tried myself to find these companies - I started on Indie Hackers, actually. I went to the Product Page and started just drilling down on each of the products. But it was a slog. Going through each one was just a tremendous effort, and frequently they are not hiring, which makes sense, since they don’t <em>need</em> to unless it really hurts.</p>

<p>The hypothesis is this:</p>
<ol>
  <li>A lot of those in the tech community are looking for a more pure experience to business. Something that doesn’t involve chasing new valuations, and overtaking the world.</li>
  <li>Independent companies hire when it hurts. They’ve figured out how to become profitable and certainly want to keep it that way.</li>
  <li>Connecting these two groups together will help give access to more talent to the independent companies and fulfill what the job seekers are looking for.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The idea came from me looking for a job myself. I became disenchanted by all the VC-backed companies. Instead, what if there was a way to find private companies, that are profitable and looking to grow. None of that magical, profitability-will-come-later business.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">97 Days</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/21/97-days.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="97 Days" /><published>2022-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/21/97-days</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/21/97-days.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been reading more and more lately. More of other people’s words. More of other people’s thoughts, ideas, concepts, opinions, and tangents. And I have started to wonder how their voice comes through so clearly - how they seem to just make words connect to each other, and I believe it just comes down to the fact that they have been doing it more, and for longer than I have.</p>

<p>So, here’s the start for me to become more regular in my own musings; develop my own voice, my own style of writing, and clarify my own thoughts into the aether.</p>

<p>100 days is too round of a number, let’s try 97 days. (It’s also prime, so it’s go that going for it) So, by <strong>checks notes</strong> March 28, 2023, I should have 96 blog posts in addition to this one.</p>

<p>Gaining clarity of thought is my goal, and maybe I’ll find some other things along the way.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been reading more and more lately. More of other people’s words. More of other people’s thoughts, ideas, concepts, opinions, and tangents. And I have started to wonder how their voice comes through so clearly - how they seem to just make words connect to each other, and I believe it just comes down to the fact that they have been doing it more, and for longer than I have.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Double</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/12/20/double.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Double" /><published>2022-12-20T11:27:59-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-20T11:27:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/12/20/double</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/12/20/double.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, for a few months now, I’ve been working on <a href="https://doubleapp.xyz">Double</a>. It’s an app that lets you do things with others online, like exercising, cooking, or working. It came as a way to fix</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, for a few months now, I’ve been working on Double. It’s an app that lets you do things with others online, like exercising, cooking, or working. It came as a way to fix]]></summary></entry></feed>