<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-05T14:43:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Lagging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/04/lagging.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lagging" /><published>2023-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/04/lagging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/04/lagging.html"><![CDATA[<p>Been finding I have been a day behind on each of these posts, usually writing what I had wanted to write the day before. But somehow, I still find it on the level and not quite cheating, because I’m still writing.</p>

<p>However, I will dedicate more time to it than I have been.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Been finding I have been a day behind on each of these posts, usually writing what I had wanted to write the day before. But somehow, I still find it on the level and not quite cheating, because I’m still writing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Good Busy Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/03/a-good-busy-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Good Busy Day" /><published>2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/03/a-good-busy-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/03/a-good-busy-day.html"><![CDATA[<p>Was a bit of a busy day - worked on some things, applied to some jobs, went to a party.</p>

<p>Good busy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Was a bit of a busy day - worked on some things, applied to some jobs, went to a party.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Source Goldilocks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/02/open-source-goldilocks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source Goldilocks" /><published>2023-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/02/open-source-goldilocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/02/open-source-goldilocks.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve become convinced that there will always be an elusive perfect library in the open source community. That is, for the purposes I’m trying to use something, all packages out there miss the mark <em>just</em> enough, that I need to go write it on my own. I know that sounds super privileged, and I fully support the OSS community - but just once, it’d be great to find a library that just <em>works</em> for me, ya know?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve become convinced that there will always be an elusive perfect library in the open source community. That is, for the purposes I’m trying to use something, all packages out there miss the mark just enough, that I need to go write it on my own. I know that sounds super privileged, and I fully support the OSS community - but just once, it’d be great to find a library that just works for me, ya know?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wine Night</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/01/wine-night.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wine Night" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/01/wine-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/01/wine-night.html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight’s wine of choice: 2015 Satellite Pinot Noir.</p>

<p>Glasses finished: 0.6</p>

<p>Glasses intended: 2?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tonight’s wine of choice: 2015 Satellite Pinot Noir.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journata</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/02/01/journata.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journata" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/02/01/journata</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/02/01/journata.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="motivation-and-hypothesis">Motivation and hypothesis</h3>
<p>I’ve been recently appreciating the brilliant design and delivery of<a href="https://pudding.cool">The Pudding</a>. And after watching a video series of how they made just <em>one</em> of their posts, it got me thinking of a way to make this form of data journalism more accessible.</p>

<p><a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost</a> has been around for a bit, and I <strong>love</strong> the philosophy behind it: open-source and writer-centric. I want to bring the same sort of accessibility as Ghost, and Substack, and Medium to data journalism. Easy to pick up, powerful underneath, lets you monetize, track subscribers, readers, send emails - all of it.</p>

<p>As of right now, writers need to write their articles and develop their plots, diagrams, and visuals separately. Sure, they can mess around with D3 a bunch, but then you create super bespoke code just for that article.</p>

<p>What if there was a way to make it simpler and repeatable but without sacrificing how customizable it can be for the power user?</p>

<p>I’m calling it, temporarily, Journata (Journal + Data, I know it’s corny.)</p>

<h3 id="how-i-plan-to-build-it">How I plan to build it</h3>

<p>I was tossing back and forth on whether to do this in SvelteKit or try Phoenix + Elixir again, but I settled on Svelte for a few reasons:</p>
<ol>
  <li>It just hit 1.0 last month, so it is much more stable</li>
  <li>It brings a bunch of nice features to the table like transitions and tweened</li>
  <li>I don’t <em>really</em> have a need for real-time information, other than maybe a real-time dashboard</li>
  <li>I’ll most likely be doing a bunch of JS anyways</li>
</ol>

<p>The absolute goal for this project is simplicity, like the last one. I want this project to be almost comically simple on the frontend, but with powerful functionality.</p>

<p>I’ve been looking into D3, and I think it’ll be helpful, but after reading through<a href="https://www.connorrothschild.com/post/svelte-scrollytelling#step-0a-understand-russells-ltscrolly-gt">this blog post</a>, it frankly looks like just doing it with Svelte components will work and allow me to leverage the power of Svelte.</p>

<p>That means, I will basically need to build a plotting library for SvelteKit.</p>

<p>(Why do I do this)</p>

<p>Soooo….here goes nothing.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="updates">Updates</h3>

<h3 id="february-1">February 1</h3>

<p>I have fleshed out the basics of the site. I have a text editor that uses markdown thanks to the<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/svelte-markdown">svelte-markdown</a> package.</p>

<p>A basic upload/drag a picture onto the page functionality is also in.</p>

<p>Verrrrryyy preliminary plotting is in. I’m talking points, scatter plot, and lines with some animations.</p>

<p>I should really draw out a diagram of how the data structures should look before I go too far - otherwise it’ll be spaghetti soon and linking all these components to scroll triggers will be difficult.</p>

<p>I do quite like the ability in svelte for all of the properties to be part of the component. That means that each of those will be accessible through a properties menu I will make where I can specify triggers for changes to that element and how to change it (e.g., change color, size, shape, location).</p>

<p>Overall, seems good so far!</p>

<p>One thing that is currently unknown is how to transport all this data to a backend - how do I serialize all of these objects and transitions, etc, in an intelligible way.</p>

<p>And how do I publish these sites? That is, how do I make it so the components are fixed in how they will appear, show, move, etc. without other people adjusting them? Maybe copying it and setting all the objects to be locked? Not sure.</p>

<h3 id="february-2">February 2</h3>

<p>Today I was basically trying to figure out how to get a scrollytelling element placed in. There was a svelte component someone made for scrollytelling, so I imported it.</p>

<p>However, I think I am going at this at the wrong direction.</p>

<p>I <strong>first</strong> need to get the visualizations working - get the property panel in place in order to adjust the visuals.</p>

<p>I looked around at visualization libraries, but what is sort of frustrating is that I still have to go in and adjust them to bake in the transitions and scrolly elements, or the plotting libraries are shipped so readily with their own CSS that it basically breaks the site.</p>

<p>So, what I am thinking is that I need to take inspiration from an existing library, add in scrolly and transition options to them, and see how it works.</p>

<p>That is, for each element on the page, there should be options for how to introduce them into the flow of scrolling. For instance, say there was a point - I should be able to say, without code: “this point should start to appear when I scroll <strong>here</strong> and it should appear using the “fly” transition, with a duration of 1 second.”</p>

<p>I suppose what I have in my head is similar to the timeline transition functionality that is present within powerpoint - the OG of visualization.</p>

<p>Tomorrow will be starting from this point and seeing where it takes me.</p>

<h3 id="february-5">February 5</h3>

<p>So, yesterday, I found<a href="https://layercake.graphics/">Layer Cake</a>. It’s a svelte graphics framework, and I think it is exactly what I need. It doesn’t just spit out plots like the others, but allows me the flexibility of what I want to do.</p>

<p>I managed to get a rough working example of a scrolly element with transitions for a plot - the kind of thing you’d see on some blogging platforms, maybe.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/journata/scrolly.gif" alt="Scrolly demo" /></p>

<p>Although the gif is rather unimpressive at first glance, it’s actually a great proof of concept. I was able to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Control the color of the line and area</li>
  <li>X and Y axis scales and limits</li>
  <li>Tick mark locations</li>
  <li>Transition type, speed, and delay</li>
  <li>Scroll triggers</li>
</ul>

<p>In essence, I was able to control just about everything about this plot almost for free. The next step will be including a property pane that exposes all of this functionality to me, letting me mess around with it without coding.</p>

<p>I can see it coming together already!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Motivation and hypothesis I’ve been recently appreciating the brilliant design and delivery ofThe Pudding. And after watching a video series of how they made just one of their posts, it got me thinking of a way to make this form of data journalism more accessible.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forgot Again</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/31/forgot-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forgot Again" /><published>2023-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/31/forgot-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/31/forgot-again.html"><![CDATA[<p>Forgot this day, but got a disco ball and put it in my living room.</p>

<p>Brightest apartment on the block, baby.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forgot this day, but got a disco ball and put it in my living room.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding Inspiration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/30/finding-inspiration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding Inspiration" /><published>2023-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/30/finding-inspiration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/30/finding-inspiration.html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspiration is probably the most elusive of experiences. I eagerly hope that it hits me, become defeated when it doesn’t, then when I am not looking for it, it comes to me.</p>

<p>It’s like the saying “a watched pot never boils”.</p>

<p>Somehow, inspiration is like repelling magnets. I turn to the idea, push towards it, but there is this invisible force pushing back, resisting me.</p>

<p>Only once I turn away, have the opposite regard towards inspiration, does it finally come to me.</p>

<p>Is it as simple as just being aloof more often?</p>

<p>Or creating more activities in my life where I don’t have to think about problems / making something?</p>

<p>Maybe that’s the same reason that I fall asleep and wake up with answers, as others do as well. It gives me time to turn my magnet around and focus on something else.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inspiration is probably the most elusive of experiences. I eagerly hope that it hits me, become defeated when it doesn’t, then when I am not looking for it, it comes to me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lunar New Year</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/29/lunar-new-year.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lunar New Year" /><published>2023-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/29/lunar-new-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/29/lunar-new-year.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I went to a hotpot place in Chinatown. Nevermind the blaring drums I heard, I was in the mood for some hotpot and went.</p>

<p>When I went there, the lunar new year festival was ongoing, with its brilliant red and yellow dragons, crackling fireworks, and crowds of onlookers.</p>

<p>I made my way inside the restaurant, only to be followed moments after by what was outside - the drums and dragons.</p>

<p>They danced around the restaurant, tossing lettuce out of their mouths, and quite frankly was one of the more unique experiences I have had in a while.</p>

<p>The hotpot was good too.</p>

<p>I got the tonkotsu broth.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I went to a hotpot place in Chinatown. Nevermind the blaring drums I heard, I was in the mood for some hotpot and went.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/28/transience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transience" /><published>2023-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/28/transience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/28/transience.html"><![CDATA[<p>Boston has a certain kind of transience. The concentration of schools lends itself for people to go to school here, get hired locally, and then maybe after a few years leave.</p>

<p>Is it like this everywhere? Is life just transient like that or am I missing something?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boston has a certain kind of transience. The concentration of schools lends itself for people to go to school here, get hired locally, and then maybe after a few years leave.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Emotionally Tired</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/27/emotionally-tired.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emotionally Tired" /><published>2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/27/emotionally-tired</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/27/emotionally-tired.html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes there are days that are just <em>days</em>, you know? Conversations are a little more weary, speaking becomes more effortful, and you’d like to just stop it all, get under the covers, and let tomorrow come already.</p>

<p>That’s where I’m at now.</p>

<p>I want tomorrow to be here.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes there are days that are just days, you know? Conversations are a little more weary, speaking becomes more effortful, and you’d like to just stop it all, get under the covers, and let tomorrow come already.]]></summary></entry></feed>