<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-17T17:00:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">You just have to listen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/12/17/listen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You just have to listen" /><published>2023-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/12/17/listen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/12/17/listen.html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I’ve been in a bit of a mental rut that I want to build something, but find myself lost for what to build. I made a little toy project for fun (<a href="https://snapress.com">snapress</a>), but finished it in a weekend and found myself longing again for something new.</p>

<p>I went to sleep last night, and maybe it was a combination of being in this longing state as well as doing a fast that day, but it was the first time in my life that I had a dream give me advice.</p>

<p>There in my dream I was essentially shadowing a version of Steve Jobs, looking at what he was looking at when it came to phones: the clunky key presses on keyboards crammed into the plastic, the long loading times of pictures on what he calls a “baby internet”, and applications that are sluggish without any real power.</p>

<p>And I watched people struggling with these things with the current knowledge now of easier interfaces, more powerful cameras, and full-fledged applications and the solution feels obvious.</p>

<p>It was then that this fictional Steve Jobs I’ve hallucinated in my dream says to me:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>They’ll be telling you the solution the whole time</p>

  <p>You just have to listen</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I woke up feeling refreshed and ready to listen instead of actively seek out new projects.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I’ve been in a bit of a mental rut that I want to build something, but find myself lost for what to build. I made a little toy project for fun (snapress), but finished it in a weekend and found myself longing again for something new.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feel Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/09/feel-alive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feel Alive" /><published>2023-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/09/feel-alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/09/feel-alive.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Forget just tryna survive
I’m only doing that which makes me feel alive</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Bahamas</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forget just tryna survive I’m only doing that which makes me feel alive]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Detail and Beauty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/06/detail-and-beauty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Detail and Beauty" /><published>2023-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/06/detail-and-beauty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/06/detail-and-beauty.html"><![CDATA[<p>Violin has been a part of my life for a little over 3 years now.</p>

<p>I’ve gone through 4 of the Suzuki books and I’m currently working on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MkmxC8UXPMM">J.S. Bach: Sonata for Violin Solo No. 3 in C Major, BWV 1005 - III. Largo</a>.</p>

<p>The piece is classic Bach: clear, beautiful, melodic lines, with intervals that are unforgiving. Needless to say, this is a tough piece for me.</p>

<p>Making progress has been rough up until my last lesson where my teacher imparted some wisdom that extends beyond just violin and is something I’ve been thinking about all day.</p>

<p>In it’s simplest form, she said this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Focus on the detail to enjoy the beauty during the process</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I wanted to hear the gorgeous lines that Bach has crafted in its entirety, and so I was practicing like that. But to properly learn to play it, I need to work from the details up. I can’t expect to play what I have listen to right out of the gate, no matter how much I want to — I have to dig into it and be specific with what I’m doing.</p>

<p>“How should this interval sound?”</p>

<p>“How does my finger feel when I play this double stop?”</p>

<p>“Can I move my wrist to make this transition more comfortable?”</p>

<p>“What if I put my second finger down first?”</p>

<p>“How much hair should my bow have here?”</p>

<p>“Where do I want to be in the bow?”</p>

<p>“Why do I hear a rogue note?”</p>

<p>“Why isn’t this note resonating right now?”</p>

<p>I should take enjoyment in the minutiae of crafting the piece from the ground up, almost as if I’m walking in Bach’s footsteps as he wrote the piece. Feel how the notes fit together – how the phrase is built and rises from simple notes.</p>

<p>Today was the first day I really put this new perspective into my practice – I was fired up. And by the time I finished practicing, the level of progress was dramatic: intervals were singing, my bow and left hand relaxed, a sense of comfort in how to navigate the notes and the phrasing.</p>

<p>It was a breakthrough.</p>

<p>The task now is how to translate this learning into other aspects of my life like eating better, building products, and writing. I suppose the first step is to first identify what what small units I can break things down into: meals, lines of code, and words, for example, and work up from there to enjoy the details while not forgetting about the bigger picture as the goal.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Violin has been a part of my life for a little over 3 years now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tossing Out The Cupcakes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/02/tossing-out-the-cupcakes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tossing Out The Cupcakes" /><published>2023-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/02/tossing-out-the-cupcakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/11/02/tossing-out-the-cupcakes.html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we hosted a Halloween party. As expected, all of our friends brought food, in addition to the food that we bought for the party: cupcakes, Oreos, chips, pretzels, candy, candy corn, and a ton of booze.</p>

<p>Well, it seems that everyone was mostly craving savory things (chips, pretzels, etc.) and not so much sweet things (cupcakes, candy). So, we were left with all of that the next day.</p>

<p>I found myself going to the kitchen multiple times to nibble on a double-stuff Oreo or two. A cupcake at noon and after dinner.</p>

<p>And then I caught myself – what am I doing? Why am I eating this?</p>

<p>I didn’t feel any joy from eating these things. I have been struggling with weight and I am just fighting against myself here.</p>

<p>So, I went to the kitchen, grabbed a trash bag, and one after another began tossing out the cupcakes and cookies that were left. I didn’t want them in my sight or in the house because I just couldn’t resist them.</p>

<p>I felt good about getting it out of the house and would rather toss it out than put it in my body anymore.</p>

<p>It was a good step forward for me and felt like a stake in the ground that I have had enough of how I’m eating.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last Friday we hosted a Halloween party. As expected, all of our friends brought food, in addition to the food that we bought for the party: cupcakes, Oreos, chips, pretzels, candy, candy corn, and a ton of booze.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guava</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/10/27/guava.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guava" /><published>2023-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/10/27/guava</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/10/27/guava.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m traveling soon. World travels. Maybe for a year or two. And, as one does, I’m going to make a blog.</p>

<p>While Jekyll has been good to me for this blog, what I want is something that is more flexible, and something I don’t have to write in markdown in VSCode and push changes.</p>

<p>No, I want dead-easy, drag-and-drop, flexible, mobile-friendly, and <em>fast</em>.</p>

<p>I want to be able to move images where I want them, add sounds of city streets as someone reads a post, be able to draw arrows right on the page to point to something interesting.</p>

<p>I want to be able to keep my family and friends up to date when a new post is there and know where I am in the world, give them the ability to add suggestions – make posts <em>multiplayer</em>.</p>

<p>There are a few platforms out there that embody similar ideals, and I’m trying to create a mashup of them.</p>

<p>My inspiration is coming from sites like:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://mmm.page">mmm.page</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bearblog.dev">Bear Blog</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost</a></li>
</ul>

<p>So, let’s get cracking!</p>

<hr />
<h3 id="october-27-2023">October 27, 2023</h3>

<p>I’ve already laid the groundwork for text and images. Namely, I’ve been able to integrate the TipTap editor into a new element, and select images.</p>

<p>Things like copy/paste, delete, resize, and drag to position are also in.</p>

<p>The main challenge right now is getting the elements to look right on both desktop and mobile. The idea is be able to specify where I’d want the element to be on the desktop and where I want it on mobile, if at all. Something like visual breakpoints for each element. By default, it would be a fixed element that, as the screen size shrinks, it goes off the page if outside the bounds.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Accidental Italian flag during testing for boundaries, but quite pleased with how the drag and drop functionality is coming! I can feel it&#39;s getting easier to put things down and get it going. <a href="https://t.co/dQU2ml8vs2">pic.twitter.com/dQU2ml8vs2</a></p>&mdash; Ian (@laskyio) <a href="https://twitter.com/laskyio/status/1717675740869628326?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 26, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m traveling soon. World travels. Maybe for a year or two. And, as one does, I’m going to make a blog.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Liking Gap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/10/27/the-liking-gap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Liking Gap" /><published>2023-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/10/27/the-liking-gap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/10/27/the-liking-gap.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been reading a book lately called Platonic (shout out to the Boston Public Library’s discover section).</p>

<p>There is this concept in it that I found rather insightful: the “liking gap”.</p>

<p>The “liking gap” is the concept that how much we perceive someone likes us is usually an underestimate of how much they actually do.</p>

<p>This can be translated into a number of scenarios.</p>

<p>For me, I’ve used this when chatting to people at events – I assume they’d like to chat and are open to connection.</p>

<p>I approach them, say hello and introduce myself, and ask a question.</p>

<p>Most recently I was at a Bahamas concert and noticed a few people next to me.</p>

<p>They weren’t initiating, so I remembered what I read about the liking gap. So, I initiated and we connected over our love of the band and chatted about their new album – it was a great connection!</p>

<p>Another recent connection is a friend I’ve been emailing back and forth with after finding their blog. I was interested in their story, and felt I could maybe offer some advice for their situation. It’s been fun so far to encourage them to start a project and to also reflect on how much I’ve grown with my technical knowledge from my own projects.</p>

<p>The best part of all this is that it is <em>repeatable</em> and <em>practicable</em>. I can do it whenever, wherever, make new connections, meet new people, learn about them and their world and maybe, just maybe, foster a new friendship.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been reading a book lately called Platonic (shout out to the Boston Public Library’s discover section).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ikigai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/09/01/ikigai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ikigai" /><published>2023-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/09/01/ikigai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/09/01/ikigai.html"><![CDATA[<p>Ikigai is a Japanese concept that roughly translates to “a reason for being”. You might have seen it floating around the internet as a Venn diagram with 4 circles: what you love, what you’re good at, what you can be paid for, and what the world needs.</p>

<p>It’s a concept I’ve been wrestling with – is this something that is sought out actively or one that occurs naturally? My answer has been slowly shaping towards 30% of the first and 70% of the second.</p>

<p>As a bit of a tangent, there’s a famous psychiatrist Dr. Phil Stutz who popularized the idea of one’s “life force”, pictured as a pyramid. At the bottom of the pyramid you have body, in the middle you have relationships, and at the top you have self.</p>

<p>When lost or in search of meaning, focusing on one or more of these levels is a way to keep movement in your life.</p>

<p>Focus on your body: start eating better, run, sleep, go outside and feel the sun warm your face – anything to get the body moving and feeling good.</p>

<p>Enrich and strengthen your relationships with others: seek out those who you want to feel connected to, show up for each other.</p>

<p>And finally, work on yourself: improve your skills, learn something new, tangential, unrelated to anything else. Focus on broadening values and experiences.</p>

<p>I’ve really been in a rut lately and have had to remind myself that things have always happened for me when I focused on my “life force” first and that I need to trust in myself. Because it is only through doing that, that I feel I can find what my own ikigai is.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ikigai is a Japanese concept that roughly translates to “a reason for being”. You might have seen it floating around the internet as a Venn diagram with 4 circles: what you love, what you’re good at, what you can be paid for, and what the world needs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Resgen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/08/14/resgen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resgen" /><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/08/14/resgen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/08/14/resgen.html"><![CDATA[<p>Will do a more formal writeup at some point, but the project is here: <a href="https://resgen.app">Resgen</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will do a more formal writeup at some point, but the project is here: Resgen]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Next steps for your application to tech.ai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/14/your-application.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next steps for your application to tech.ai" /><published>2023-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/14/your-application</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/14/your-application.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi there, {applicant}!</p>

<p>We’re so happy that you expressed your interest in joining <strong>tech.ai</strong> — the leading AI company transforming the {industry} industry (and is <em>definitely not</em> just an API call to OpenAI)!</p>

<p>We have received your application and are happy to move you on to the first round which is a take-home assignment which shouldn’t take you more than 2-3 weeks. We hope you have as much fun completing it as we have had designing it! It’s designed to test a variety of skills such as:</p>

<ul>
  <li>perseverance</li>
  <li>obedience</li>
  <li>how much shit you can take</li>
  <li>your desperation for a job</li>
  <li>coding!</li>
</ul>

<p>We’ve attached the prompt for the first round to this email, it’s a quick 22 page read to give you sufficient background into the problem. (Hint: don’t forget the quirk on page 17!).</p>

<p>The expected output is a report document that is expected to contain UML diagrams, Figma wireframes, burndown charts of your progress, a picture of a pony, and a detailed document of your approach and reasoning for each line of code. Additionally, we expect the project to be completed in both python 2.7 and 3.11 - we advise creating a docker image of your project so we can run it on our end.</p>

<p>To give you a peek at the rest of the process - we’ve optimized it for speed since we are <strong>urgently hiring</strong>. So, if you are deemed worthy enough to pass the first stage, the rest of the interview process will look like the following (subject to change):</p>

<ol>
  <li>Recruiter phone screen to go over your resume [30 min]</li>
  <li>Live coding and behavioral interview [60 min]</li>
  <li>Chat with Product Manager [45 min]</li>
  <li>Second take-home assignment [2-3 weeks]</li>
  <li>Review of first and second take-home assignments [10 min]</li>
  <li>Behavioral interview with principal engineer [30 mins]</li>
  <li>Third take-home assignment [2-3 weeks]</li>
  <li>Presentation of third take-home to hiring panel [3 hours]</li>
  <li>Meet and greet with other engineers [60 min]</li>
  <li>2 month paid working trial [2 months]</li>
  <li>Chat with CPO [60 mins]</li>
  <li>Wait 2 weeks while we see if there is someone else [2 weeks]</li>
  <li>Offer!</li>
</ol>

<p>We’ve carefully crafted all 13 steps above to help make the process easy and ensure that there is a good fit — the hiring process goes both ways, after all!</p>

<p>Due to the high volume of applicants, we can’t guarantee that we’ll get back to you with detailed feedback of your take-home assignment, but we’ll make sure to maybe skim some of the first page.</p>

<p>Thanks again for your interest in tech.ai! We can’t wait to have you on board.</p>

<p>Sincerely,</p>

<p>{recruiter}</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi there, {applicant}!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We need more whimsical products</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/26/whimsy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We need more whimsical products" /><published>2023-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/26/whimsy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/26/whimsy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever seen Maxim Vengerov play? If not, check out one of my favorite performances of his:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bg1NUBLK1tk" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Here’s another with Itzhak Perlman:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QCKL95HAdQ8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>A third with Ray Chen:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I03Hs6dwj7E" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>And for good measure, here’s a fourth from Hilary Hahn:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iEBX_ouEw1I" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Okay, I mostly just wanted to share some of my favorite violinists, but I also wanted to talk about <em>why</em> I like them so much and how that reason also propagates into why I like certain products just the same.</p>

<p>If you look closely, each of these violinists have a certain whimsical nature to their playing. This isn’t to say their playing is funny, but it’s playful (even for such an intense piece as Ysaye 3), it has an interest to it that’s plastered all over their face in their playing and then rebounds into their sound - it’s electric to watch. If you have a few spare moments, I really encourage you to take some time to watch the performances above.</p>

<p>Whether it was this whimsical nature that has made them stand out originally, or it came out <em>because</em> they’re so good, I don’t know. But I am willing to bet that it is more of the former than the latter.</p>

<p>This same idea translates directly to some products I enjoy using just because the creator took the time to add in some whimsy to it. One I quite like, and use regularly, is Pocketbase. Let’s look:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/pocketbase.gif" alt="pocketbase" /></p>

<p>How fun is that! Let’s take a look at another. Here’s Bearblog:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/bearblog.gif" alt="bearblog" /></p>

<p>Let’s take a look at a third - Posthog. I mean, just <em>look</em> at their homepage, whimsy is all over the place and I’m here for it.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog1.png" alt="posthog1" />
<img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog2.png" alt="posthog2" />
<img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog3.png" alt="posthog3" />
<img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog4.png" alt="posthog4" /></p>

<p>Software can come across so serious sometimes, but when I think the products that really appeal to me, they are ones that don’t take themselves so seriously. It adds some humanity and fun back into the software world. If you know of more products that have whimsy like this, I’d love to hear about them!</p>

<p>Okay, just one more because the sites made on it really capture that early internet aesthetic: <a href="https://mmm.page">mmm.page</a></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/mmmpage.gif" alt="mmm.page" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever seen Maxim Vengerov play? If not, check out one of my favorite performances of his:]]></summary></entry></feed>