<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-26T14:55:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">We need more whimsical products</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/26/whimsy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We need more whimsical products" /><published>2023-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/26/whimsy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/26/whimsy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever seen Maxim Vengerov play? If not, check out one of my favorite performances of his:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bg1NUBLK1tk" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Here’s another with Itzhak Perlman:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QCKL95HAdQ8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>A third with Ray Chen:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I03Hs6dwj7E" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>And for good measure, here’s a fourth from Hilary Hahn:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iEBX_ouEw1I" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Okay, I mostly just wanted to share some of my favorite violinists, but I also wanted to talk about <em>why</em> I like them so much and how that reason also propagates into why I like certain products just the same.</p>

<p>If you look closely, each of these violinists have a certain whimsical nature to their playing. This isn’t to say their playing is funny, but it’s playful (even for such an intense piece as Ysaye 3), it has an interest to it that’s plastered all over their face in their playing and then rebounds into their sound - it’s electric to watch. If you have a few spare moments, I really encourage you to take some time to watch the performances above.</p>

<p>Whether it was this whimsical nature that has made them stand out originally, or it came out <em>because</em> they’re so good, I don’t know. But I am willing to bet that it is more of the former than the latter.</p>

<p>This same idea translates directly to some products I enjoy using just because the creator took the time to add in some whimsy to it. One I quite like, and use regularly, is Pocketbase. Let’s look:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/pocketbase.gif" alt="pocketbase" /></p>

<p>How fun is that! Let’s take a look at another. Here’s Bearblog:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/bearblog.gif" alt="bearblog" /></p>

<p>Let’s take a look at a third - Posthog. I mean, just look at their homepage, whimsy is all over the place and I’m here for it.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog1.png" alt="posthog1" />
<img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog2.png" alt="posthog2" />
<img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog3.png" alt="posthog3" />
<img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/posthog4.png" alt="posthog4" /></p>

<p>Software can come across so serious sometimes, but when I think the products that really appeal to me, they are ones that don’t take themselves so seriously. It adds some humanity and fun back into the software world. If you know of more products that have whimsy like this, I’d love to hear about them!</p>

<p>Okay, just one more because the sites made on it really capture that early internet aesthetic: <a href="https://mmm.page">mmm.page</a></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-07-26-whimsy/mmmpage.gif" alt="mmm.page" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever seen Maxim Vengerov play? If not, check out one of my favorite performances of his:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whiplash</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/21/whiplash.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whiplash" /><published>2023-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/21/whiplash</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/21/whiplash.html"><![CDATA[<p>I think one of my favorite movies has to be Whiplash. (Warning, there will be spoilers)</p>

<p>It’s climactic ending where Andrew plays at the JVC is always gripping to watch. If you aren’t familiar and don’t mind spoilers, Andrew is initially fooled by Fletcher that he will play the standard charts he’s used to back at school. Instead, an unfamiliar chart is put in front of him, and he flounders when he doesn’t know the chart.</p>

<p>Andrew storms off of the stage to an embrace from his father, only to return to the stage moments after.</p>

<p>It’s this part that I love.</p>

<p>He comes back on stage and there’s a coolness about him - an air of “fuck you, I will do what I want.” And I just <em>love</em> it. He takes command of the one-way power dynamic that has been presented the whole movie and, instead of Fletcher determining the situation, Andrew is in charge.</p>

<p>The father, just on the side of the stage and after being doubtful of the path his son is on all movie, finally “gets it” how his son is great - how he is consumed by his passion, maybe obsessed.</p>

<p>There’s a single shot that I think about a lot. It’s where Andrew is playing his solo, and there is a shot of the bass drum rocking back and forth. It’s maybe a 1 second shot, if that. And with the sound of the drums, it feels like it’s a car pushing its absolute limits, with the motor whirring at peak RPM. It’s stable, but by just a hair. It’s physically showing just how at the limit he is.</p>

<p>I aspire to be at the limits of something, pushing the boundaries and bringing something into this world that did not exist before.</p>

<p>Sure, these are just words and the work is in the doing. But god dammit, I’m trying.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think one of my favorite movies has to be Whiplash. (Warning, there will be spoilers)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Make it slick and be the only user</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/20/simple-lovable-complete.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make it slick and be the only user" /><published>2023-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/20/simple-lovable-complete</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/20/simple-lovable-complete.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="slc---simple-lovable-and-complete">SLC - Simple, Lovable, and Complete</h2>
<p>I read a post a little while ago on Bearblog called <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/mvp-vs-slc/">“Why products should be ‘slick’, not just viable”</a>, and it really resonated with me.</p>

<p>Instead of using MVP (minimum viable product) as the measure of an incremental unit of a product, he uses SLC (simple, lovable, and complete). In essence, SLC is the idea that the product should be complete from the onset – that even though there <em>could</em> be more added to the product, it doesn’t necessarily need to in order to operate as its main function.</p>

<p>However, the key difference between SLC and MVP, in my eyes, is the L – lovable. Take, for instance, ChatGPT. It’s a cha box. That’s it. Chat has been around forever. The design is not new.</p>

<p>But it’s lovable. It was (until Threads, maybe) the fastest growing service ever because it was just that good.</p>

<h2 id="i-am-the-only-user">I am the only user</h2>
<p>There’s another idea that also resonated - <a href="https://blubsblog.bearblog.dev/i-am-the-only-user/">being the only user.</a>From this one, I gained the insight that my products that I have developed previously were for some ephemeral “user” that I thought I identified with. However, when developing the product, I quickly became aware that I wouldn’t use it ever, let alone <em>pay</em> for it.</p>

<p>So, I started to truly look for problems in my own life, ones that I actually become angry at because “why is it like this? How has there been <strong><em>nothing</em></strong> to solve this yet?”</p>

<p>I’ve found 2 problems and because they were truly <em>my</em> problems, I was able to quickly solve them. (I’ll make a couple project posts about them soon)</p>

<h2 id="bringing-it-together">Bringing it together</h2>

<p>The last thing I have learned is that it really is that these two concepts work in tandem with each other. To build something SLC, I first have to build something that I would love. It doesn’t have to be complete for me, but I should make sure that it is complete for others, if I want to share it, without ruining the simplicity of the hacky solution.</p>

<p>So, first develop for yourself and solve your pain points. Then keep the simplicity and make it lovable to use.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SLC - Simple, Lovable, and Complete I read a post a little while ago on Bearblog called “Why products should be ‘slick’, not just viable”, and it really resonated with me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Still Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/05/01/still-alive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Still Alive" /><published>2023-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/05/01/still-alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/05/01/still-alive.html"><![CDATA[<p>Went to Italy. Back in Boston. Still alive. Looking for the next thing.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Went to Italy. Back in Boston. Still alive. Looking for the next thing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Breaks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/16/breaks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaks" /><published>2023-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/16/breaks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/16/breaks.html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my friends told me about a quote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Take breaks, not stops</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I took a break from writing everyday. I found I became very in my head, tossing things around that, while yes they were good to get down, made me ruminate too much and put me into a bit of a hole.</p>

<p>I’m back now and feeling refreshed.</p>

<p>I have a trip to Italy in less than two weeks, where I hope to make my sense of self even more whole.</p>

<p>A new idea has been stuck in my brain, one about learning. It is similar to the flashcard project idea I had, but a little more expansive. I’ll create a post of that separately.</p>

<hr />

<p>Other benefits that I have noticed about myself have been that I have not stepped on the scale once. It has brought a new kind of peace to myself. Where I don’t tie myself to a number and don’t let it define me. I have been going to the gym, feeling stronger each day, eating better, and embracing the difference day by day.</p>

<p>I have to remind myself that this is my year of simplicity. My year of embracing how simple things can prove the most enjoyable - how the simple things are the ones that end up making me happier all around.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of my friends told me about a quote:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sourdough Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/01/sourdough-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sourdough Part 2" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/01/sourdough-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/01/sourdough-part-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s alive! Bubbly and smelling sour - need to feed it. Hopefully will have a loaf ready for this weekend!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s alive! Bubbly and smelling sour - need to feed it. Hopefully will have a loaf ready for this weekend!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jobs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/28/jobs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jobs" /><published>2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/28/jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/28/jobs.html"><![CDATA[<p>Applying to jobs. Not much else.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Applying to jobs. Not much else.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Tools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/27/the-tools.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Tools" /><published>2023-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/27/the-tools</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/27/the-tools.html"><![CDATA[<p>Decided to watch the movie Stutz, which is about Jonah Hill’s therapist, Phil Stutz. He’s a well-known therapist in Hollywood, but that was the first I’ve ever heard of him. And frankly, the ideas presented are going to help me change things.</p>

<p>Even from just watching, hearing the phrasing about the Shadow, and relating to Hill that my shadow is a younger, overweight self, it finally clicked to have compassion for that self. It is a part of me. My Shadow would feel bad for how I have thought of him. I feel bad for thinking of him the same way others may have thought of him, despite knowing him the best.</p>

<p>I also downloaded his two audio books, The Tools and Coming Alive, written with Barry Michels. I plan to take these tools into practice.</p>

<p>It’ll take a bit of adjustment to the language, which frankly sounds a little loopy. But hey, most ideas sound loopy before you try them. Especially the good ones.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decided to watch the movie Stutz, which is about Jonah Hill’s therapist, Phil Stutz. He’s a well-known therapist in Hollywood, but that was the first I’ve ever heard of him. And frankly, the ideas presented are going to help me change things.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slump</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/26/slump.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slump" /><published>2023-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/26/slump</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/26/slump.html"><![CDATA[<p>How do I get out of a slump? I exercise a few times a weak, my eating is kind of bleh, but every time I try I end up back at the same point.</p>

<p>Maybe there are different avenues to the same destination for getting out of the slump.</p>

<p>I was reminded of the 4000 week idea recently, and I feel like I just burned one or two that will never be coming back. How can I treasure the remaining weeks?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I get out of a slump? I exercise a few times a weak, my eating is kind of bleh, but every time I try I end up back at the same point.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sourdough</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/25/sourdough.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sourdough" /><published>2023-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/25/sourdough</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/25/sourdough.html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to make bread. A lot of bread. Baguettes, boules, croissants - you get it.</p>

<p>For a holiday gift exchange at my previous work, I received a packet of sourdough starter and Flour, Water, Salt, Yeast. I know I am very late to the sourdough train, but I figured I will start baking again. Last time I remember doing it, it brought a tremendous joy to my life.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I used to make bread. A lot of bread. Baguettes, boules, croissants - you get it.]]></summary></entry></feed>