<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-08T10:02:03-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Sick, Inside, and Taking it Easy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/06/sick-inside-and-taking-it-easy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sick, Inside, and Taking it Easy" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/06/sick-inside-and-taking-it-easy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/06/sick-inside-and-taking-it-easy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a bit of a blah day.</p>

<p>A day I woke up sick, checked myself for covid (negative), and proceeded to just lounge about for a while working on <a href="/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs.html">Indie Comp Jobs</a>.</p>

<p>Lots of cough drops.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was a bit of a blah day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing Improvement</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/05/writing-improvement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing Improvement" /><published>2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/05/writing-improvement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/05/writing-improvement.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is the 17th day in a row that I have written something and placed it out into the world, regardless if someone is reading it.</p>

<p>And I have to say, that I feel like my voice is starting to really come through in my writing; I am becoming bolder, making the words flow a bit nicer, and developing a tone of my own.</p>

<p>As I have been writing more, I’ve noticed a few new traits I exhibit:</p>
<ul>
  <li>I like to write things in threes. There’s a certain completeness of threes, a rhythm, a “hey those two previous things were nice, but here’s an excellent number 3.” I dunno, just going to go with it - it seems natural.</li>
  <li>Hyphens are my way, and I suppose a lot of people’s way, of just getting to the point of the sentence. No more long winded essays - I just get to the point. Just like that. They’re snappy and immediate.</li>
  <li>Here’s a third bullet. See bullet 1.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today is the 17th day in a row that I have written something and placed it out into the world, regardless if someone is reading it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Barley Tea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/04/barley-tea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Barley Tea" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/04/barley-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/04/barley-tea.html"><![CDATA[<p>Barley tea has been a relatively new discovery for myself. It is exactly what it sounds like: barley boiled in hot water.</p>

<p>But I find myself basically chugging it now.</p>

<p>That slight bit of toasty, warm-by-the-fire, safe-in-my-little-cottage flavor seems to keep calling me back - and it isn’t even that strong of a flavor. It just whispers to me and draws me in for another sip.</p>

<p>I want to make more things like barley tea; things that keep calling me back with their simplicity and always provide just the right amount of delight.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barley tea has been a relatively new discovery for myself. It is exactly what it sounds like: barley boiled in hot water.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lentil Soup Entropy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/03/lentil-soup-entropy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lentil Soup Entropy" /><published>2023-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/03/lentil-soup-entropy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/03/lentil-soup-entropy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I made some delicious lentil soup. I added a bit of heavy cream into it and watched the vortices within the soup as I moved my ladle through it. It made me think back to the show<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt8134186/">Devs</a> and what it would take to simulate such entropy. There must be millions of people making soup a day, all with their own little vortices. How many FLOPS would it take to reverse everyone’s soup that day? I feel like we are not even close to the computing power to simulate that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I made some delicious lentil soup. I added a bit of heavy cream into it and watched the vortices within the soup as I moved my ladle through it. It made me think back to the showDevs and what it would take to simulate such entropy. There must be millions of people making soup a day, all with their own little vortices. How many FLOPS would it take to reverse everyone’s soup that day? I feel like we are not even close to the computing power to simulate that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elixir And Phoenix</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/02/elixir-and-phoenix.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elixir And Phoenix" /><published>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/02/elixir-and-phoenix</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/02/elixir-and-phoenix.html"><![CDATA[<p>As I have been learning Elixir, it was only natural that I discovered the<a href="https://phoenixframework.org">Phoenix Framework</a> along with it.</p>

<p>At first glance, it seems sort of similar to Django with a MVC framework (or a MVT, or MVCT - you get it), but with the added benefit of being built on top of a much more concurrent language, Elixir (which, in turn, is built upon Erlang). This means that channels and presence essentially fall out of the framework - this is awesome.</p>

<p>I previously read through the blog by Uku Taht of Plausible on his<a href="https://plausible.io/blog/technology-choices">technology choices</a> and he also went with Phoenix and Elixir for similar reasons. Given that Plausible is open-source, I plan to take a look through the codebase to learn a bit more.</p>

<p>In addition, I am using Elixir to make a new project,<a href="/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs.html"><strong><em>Indie Comp Jobs</em></strong></a>. It might seem a <em>bit</em> overkill for such an idea, but I definitely want to dip my toes into this technology as I can already see it becoming huge across the industry. Also, it looks like a PaaS, Fly.io, is built on-top of Phoenix with extensive support. So, once I become more familiar with the language &amp; framework, it would not only be easier to make performant web apps, but deploying them will be a breeze.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I have been learning Elixir, it was only natural that I discovered thePhoenix Framework along with it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Indie Comp Jobs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indie Comp Jobs" /><published>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="motivation-and-hypothesis">Motivation and hypothesis</h3>
<p>The idea came from me looking for a job myself. I became disenchanted trying to find a job from a non-VC-backed company. It was (and still is) legitimately difficult to do so. So, I thought: what if there was a way to find private companies that are profitable and looking to grow? None of that magical, profitability-will-come-later business that is so frequent with VC-backed startups.</p>

<p>I tried myself to find these companies - I started on Indie Hackers, actually. I went to the Product Page and started just drilling down on each of the products. But it was a slog. Going through each one was just a tremendous effort, and frequently they are not hiring, which makes sense, since they don’t <em>need</em> to unless it really hurts.</p>

<p>So, my hypothesis is that in this two-sided marketplace, there are these characteristics of the job seekers and the companies:</p>
<ul>
  <li>There is a growing sentiment in the tech community to look for more meaningful work rather than just chasing the salaries. Something that doesn’t involve going after new valuations, overtaking the world, and can provide a good balance.</li>
  <li>Independent companies hire when it hurts. They’ve figured out how to become profitable and certainly want to keep it that way.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-i-plan-to-build-it">How I plan to build it</h3>

<p>I plan to built it using<a href="https://phoenixproject.org">Phoenix.</a> It is, in part, a way to learn more about Elixir and Phoenix, but also to incorporate some little “hey, that’s kinda cool” effects along the way that I know would be a pain in the ass otherwise.</p>

<p>I’m taking inspiration from<a href="https://japan-dev.com">Japan Dev</a> and<a href="https://remoteok.com">Remote | OK</a>, borrowing a bit from each. Namely, I like Remoteok’s idea of first finding jobs to populate and become, essentially, a link aggregator initially to build the job-seeker side of the market. But I also like Japan Dev’s idea of being paid <em>after</em> the applicant gets the job, making it lower-stakes for the companies to post.</p>

<p>As for monetization, I want to eventually rely solely on companies posting their jobs, and maybe some add-on services like visibility boosts. But I’m not worried about that right now. I just want people using it.</p>

<h3 id="timeline">Timeline</h3>

<p>I’m giving myself a month to try to flesh out a working prototype, source the jobs, and get people on the platform using it.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="updates">Updates</h2>

<p>I’ll be adding updates here as I continue to build. Here we go!</p>

<h3 id="jan-3">Jan 3</h3>

<p>I spent the majority of today trying to get my head around Phoenix. It’s pretty much like drinking from a firehose, I’ll admit. So, I decided, that for at least this first project, I want to focus on figuring out how to push it out fast and get people using it.</p>

<p>So, I switched back to SvelteKit (which just reached 1.0!), and make a quick mock-up of functionality. Took about 45 minutes or so.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/indiecompjobs/screenshot-2023-01-03.png" alt="Indie Comp Screenshot" /></p>

<p>I linked it up with a new (to me) ORM,<a href="https://www.prisma.io">Prisma</a>, to get some initial data flow, and it works like a charm. I can add to the database as I need, collect emails and do what I need with them.</p>

<p>The thing I want to tackle tomorrow is dealing with a bit of authentication, since I don’t want just anyone being able to post to the job board.</p>

<p>I also found some sources to find independent companies, or bootstrapped companies on <a href="https://dealroom.co">dealroom.co</a>. Their suite and jobs leave a lot to be desired and it is difficult to navigate to the point I was actually able to see the bootstrap companies. I’ll continue searching for other ways to find these companies and start creating a list of them to look for jobs (both for myself and the board).</p>

<h3 id="jan-4">Jan 4</h3>

<p>Well, it is deployed! (Kind of)</p>

<p>As a summary, today I:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Did a visual overhaul (seen below)</li>
  <li>Added in filter functionality for tags</li>
  <li>Added in some nice little visual cues for where to click (like on the apply button, for instance)</li>
  <li>Set up a CockroachDB</li>
  <li>Deployed to Vercel</li>
</ul>

<p>Overall, the deployment was relatively easy - but it was a bit of a learning curve still. I have deployed other projects before (which were much harder), so this was easy in comparison. I feel like there should still be an easier way to do it, but I don’t really know enough about it yet for how I’d go about doing it.</p>

<p>I did some more visual adjustments - I find these to be the most enjoyable of all. I can’t paint, but figuring out how to get things to look exactly as I want them is as close as I will get to being a good painter. However, it still feels as thought it is missing <em>something</em> - some zhuzh. I think the blank white (or off-white) is really throwing me. I’ll keep hacking at it.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/indiecompjobs/screenshot-2023-01-04.png" alt="New HomePage" /></p>

<p>For tomorrow, my plan is to finish up the looks and start populating with actual data. I already know it will take some time to do this (currently only able to really do it via the Prisma studio), so maybe I’ll make a page to create posts (both for me and as well as for future employers).</p>

<h3 id="january-5">January 5</h3>

<p>Today was a bit uneventful. Rearranged how the svelte files look. Also been debating going for a pure minimalism kind of feel. Something along the lines of<a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bearblog</a>.</p>

<p>I want it to be solely focused on the job, the company, and the position. Nothing else, no fluff. So, maybe I’ll try to whip up something similar tomorrow. Maybe I’ll go back to Django for this? Thinking down the line, authentication is a bit underdeveloped within the SvelteKit community (although I still need to give<a href="https://vercel.com/blog/announcing-sveltekit-auth">SvelteKit Auth</a> a try).</p>

<p>Let’s see if I can really bare-bones the site tomorrow. I want it crisp and minimal, but not unpolished (if that makes sense).</p>

<h3 id="january-6">January 6</h3>

<p>Okay - so, I know I restarted this project like 3 times now, all with different frameworks, but I redid it again with Django. Just all django. Really simply. I borrowed a lot of inspiration from Bear blog, like I mentioned yesterday, and frankly, I am a huge fan of how it is looking. I mean just look at this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/indiecompjobs/screenshot-2023-01-06.png" alt="Minimalist screen shot" /></p>

<p>The other one - before, felt…cheap? Like a site I would accidentally get redirected to while trying to find a movie for free and I click on the wrong play button. But this, just the simple html (even with a dark mode), feels, for lack of a better term, pure. (I know, I kinda got nauseous writing that too.)</p>

<p>Anyways, the benefit of this is that Django’s auth is all batteries included. I have Sendgrid set up, emails working great, and able to use Django’s admin panel to add things manually to start.</p>

<p>Still trying to figure out the best way to transition from posting things myself to setting up payment, but I suppose that is putting the cart before the horse. Anyways, glad I got it to this stage (again) today.</p>

<p>It’s live at https://indiecompjobs.com, too.</p>

<h3 id="january-7">January 7</h3>

<p>I fleshed out the website a bit more today. I added the ability to remove the job from your dashboard, as well as implemented a hotness metric to rank the jobs based upon the posting date and how many people applied.</p>

<p>I used the following equation to calculate hotness, which is pretty generic. If I feel the need to modify it in the future, I will.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>order = math.log10(max(self.num_apply, 1))
seconds = self.created_at.timestamp() - 1673063024
hours = 12.5
hotness = round(order + seconds / (hours * 3600), 15)  
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I removed the ability to post a job for the meantime, as I want to focus on adding jobs manually and getting people to check it out.</p>

<p>Additionally, I added some lightweight metrics from<a href="https://goatcounter.com">Goat Counter</a>, which are GDPR compliant, free for light traffic, and lightweight. Seemed like I should give them a shot.</p>

<p>Anyways, on to figuring out how to find all these jobs, both for me to apply to, and figure out how to source.</p>

<p>One interesting thing that has come out of it is that I can find these companies, but they don’t have RSS feeds for their jobs sites. So, keeping track of them can be a bit difficult. There are some sites that can make RSS feeds out of websites, but none seem to quite work the way I want.</p>

<p>Potentially I can just add them to a list of companies and get an RSS feed of the giants like indeed.com or something and just filter based on those companies. Not sure yet what the winning strategy is, but will keep plugging.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Motivation and hypothesis The idea came from me looking for a job myself. I became disenchanted trying to find a job from a non-VC-backed company. It was (and still is) legitimately difficult to do so. So, I thought: what if there was a way to find private companies that are profitable and looking to grow? None of that magical, profitability-will-come-later business that is so frequent with VC-backed startups.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Year Of Simplicity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/01/year-of-simplicity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Year Of Simplicity" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/01/year-of-simplicity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/01/year-of-simplicity.html"><![CDATA[<p>I walked along the water today and took time to look ahead to the new year. It was uncharacteristically warm for this time of year, but because of the wind, I wore a coat anyways.</p>

<p>During the walk, I had a realization of how deeply my physical health is linked to my mental health. “Duh”, you might being saying, and it’s true I knew it is intricately linked as well, but I had somehow forgotten that connection existed.</p>

<p>I’ve lost weight and gained weight over the years. Overall, I’m still down more than 80 pounds from my heaviest, but I’ve let myself slip this past year, gaining another 40 or so. I feel it physically, of course: I run out of breath a bit easier, my clothes are tighter, I sweat a bit more. It absolutely fucking sucks.</p>

<p>But I don’t think I fully embraced the mental effects being physically unhealthy can have. It seems as though clouds are always over my head, I don’t look in mirrors much, and I often become suspicious of someone complimenting my appearance.</p>

<p>This year, though, I’ve decided is my <strong>Year of Simplicity</strong> and I am embracing the fact that I <em>can</em> become healthy and happy with my body.</p>

<p><em>Simplicity</em> will take a variety of forms and meanings as the year progresses, but I am first starting by simplifying how I approach my health. With respect to my diet, I will simplify what I eat, when I eat, and how much I eat. Simple foods, no processed foods (paleo might be the closest, but I don’t want to place it into a bucket).</p>

<p>I’m also simplifying how I exercise - going back to my regular gym regimen. Lift weights, place them down. Do some cardio. Play some ice hockey. Lift, move, rest.</p>

<p>I think back to the periods of time I was doing this well, and those were the most productive, active, and positive times in my life. For some reason, I never attributed my emotions of those periods to the fact that my health was in check, but damn does it make sense now.</p>

<p>Here’s to simplicity.</p>

<p>Here’s to health.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I walked along the water today and took time to look ahead to the new year. It was uncharacteristically warm for this time of year, but because of the wind, I wore a coat anyways.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Panic Attack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/31/panic-attack.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Panic Attack" /><published>2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/31/panic-attack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/31/panic-attack.html"><![CDATA[<p>I think I need to move.</p>

<p>Somewhere else.</p>

<p>Somewhere with more green, more air that smells like what candles fail to emulate.</p>

<p>Somewhere I don’t have panic attacks anymore.</p>

<p>Crossing the street shoulder-to-shoulder, hearing the din of multiple overlapping conversations with my mind trying to make sense of each at the same time - I become overwhelmed.</p>

<p>My heart rate increases, my breath becomes shorter - “Get out”. Even as I’m writing this, there are fireworks going off, and I feel a bit claustrophobic despite being in my own apartment.</p>

<p>I find I have more sensitive hearing that most, with it most likely being<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misophonia">misophonia</a>or something similar.</p>

<p>People walking behind me and having their own conversation quickly overtakes my attention to my own conversation. I need to pause and look a different direction when fire engines pass with their sirens on.</p>

<p>I become angry. My fight-or-flight response is activated, I furrow my brow, my face becomes tense, I walk faster - I feel embarrassed.</p>

<p>It’s happened at work too, on the few times I went into the office. A crowded kitchen table combined with poor sound dampening resulted in complete auditory overload and an ensuing panic attack.</p>

<p>I miss out on things because of this: afterparties and going to bars with friends become deeply uncomfortable. Visiting popular areas while traveling mean I want to leave immediately and miss why I went.</p>

<p>Even though there is this thing I struggle with, the bright side is I can listen well. I can detect nuanced changes in someone’s voice, hear if the oven is on by the faint click in the other room, or easily find a phone if it’s on vibrate.</p>

<p>I’m not sure if there’s a lesson here other than the fact that I should change my environment to be one that is more conducive for me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think I need to move.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Skating</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/30/skating.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skating" /><published>2022-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/30/skating</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/30/skating.html"><![CDATA[<p>Went ice skating yesterday and today. I used to play ice hockey - I missed the feeling of effortlessly gliding around.</p>

<p>While skating, I also had a thought about design of things and how the best tools I’ve ever used feel like an extension of myself, like my skates: I don’t feel like I am off the ice - I feel firmly planted on the ice.</p>

<p>But when I am at my computer, it feels like I’m using a computer; or when I use my phone, it feels like I’m using my phone.</p>

<p>Not sure what to make of it just yet.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Went ice skating yesterday and today. I used to play ice hockey - I missed the feeling of effortlessly gliding around.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dumplings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/29/dumplings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dumplings" /><published>2022-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/29/dumplings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/12/29/dumplings.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been making dumplings at home more recently (pork dumplings, to be exact, but that’s neither here nor there). And I’ve been finding them to be a wondrous joy to make. Taking the time to experiment, practice making the “perfect” dumpling, and using my hands to make something tangible with an immediate pay-off culminates in a rich, human experience.</p>

<p>I’ve started to become aware of brands of wrappers that are better than others because they can’t be pinched as easily, have a little too much flour, or aren’t as stretchy as others.</p>

<p>I’ve discovered some techniques on how best to stuff the dumplings to not leave too much wrapper left over or overstuff them.</p>

<p>I’ve even started to figure out how to make them a bit more decorative with folds.</p>

<p>Granted, these dumplings are not as pretty as the ones you find in a restaurant, <strong><em>but they’re mine</em></strong> - and that makes all the difference.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been making dumplings at home more recently (pork dumplings, to be exact, but that’s neither here nor there). And I’ve been finding them to be a wondrous joy to make. Taking the time to experiment, practice making the “perfect” dumpling, and using my hands to make something tangible with an immediate pay-off culminates in a rich, human experience.]]></summary></entry></feed>