<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-12T21:18:01-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Connections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/12/connections.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Connections" /><published>2023-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/12/connections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/12/connections.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been thinking of connections lately and the various forms they can take. I’m going to start with a definition of connection and work from there:</p>

<p><strong><em>Connection</em></strong> (n): <em>a relationship in which a person, thing, or idea is linked or associated with something else.</em></p>

<p>Okay, so there is a relationship between people, things, or ideas. That makes sense. But now the question comes up: how do we connect people, things, or ideas?</p>

<p>Language could be one answer.</p>

<p>Being in close physical proximity is another.</p>

<p>So is being in the same place as someone in the past.</p>

<p>Of course, there are infinitely many more types of connections, but I wanted to illustrate it with these first.</p>

<p>If we take each dimension of connection one at a time, we can start to find interesting limitations to each, with respective opportunities as well.</p>

<p>For the first connection, language, the obvious is the <em>language barrier</em>. Different languages, different cultures, maybe enough to say “hello” to each other but not much else. What is being done within the language barrier space?</p>

<ul>
  <li>Language learning apps</li>
  <li>Text to Speech Translation</li>
  <li>Speech to Speech Translation</li>
  <li>Real-time audio translation</li>
</ul>

<p>But it’s still not quite there, is it? I can’t go to Korea and put in my AirPods and instantly understand everything around me. So, there is still work to be done. This is not to say that I don’t think learning a language is valuable in its own right. In fact, I’m learning Korean right now because there are certain phrases there that just don’t have an English translation.</p>

<p>Let’s take a look at the second type of connection: being in close proximity to each other. Airplanes, cars, trains, boats, bicycles, and buses have certainly made this more feasible to connect over time. But there are still instances where being in close proximity just isn’t feasible. The pandemic made this especially clear, and so a new wave of remote friendly companies aimed at making it <em>feel</em> like you’re close have popped up. But they don’t feel like anything. They feel like yet another app. Another set of lights on the screen.</p>

<p>So, what are we to do? Well, AR/VR certainly have progressed, but until they are not so damn goofy, they will not be mainstream. This is clearly a big area of investment as companies have poured billions into figuring out how to make remote work not completely wreck their “culture”.</p>

<p>Lastly, being in the same place as someone in the past can be an interesting connection. One of the first thoughts I had was about how cave drawings from millennia prior are still on the walls. Some of the earliest paintings were just our hands with paint. The hands look the same. They’re still human. But somehow we feel connected to them, standing where they stood when they made those paintings.</p>

<p>There have been <em>some</em> developments in this space, but I feel it is more open than the others. Most of it is about overlaying historic images on a scene, the same way some ruins have a glass pane you can look through to see the monument as it once stood. But can I see the people passing by? Can I hear the sounds of people during the day?</p>

<p>I think there are <strong><em>a lot</em></strong> of interesting concepts than can erupt from mulling over the various dimensions of connection, their limitations, and how we are progressing in overcoming them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking of connections lately and the various forms they can take. I’m going to start with a definition of connection and work from there:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Got My Violin Back</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/11/got-my-violin-back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Got My Violin Back" /><published>2023-01-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/11/got-my-violin-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/11/got-my-violin-back.html"><![CDATA[<p>My violin was in the shop for a bit due to a split seam and for needing a bridge adjustment. I got it back today and, after practicing on the loaner instrument, reminded myself why I invested into getting a good instrument.</p>

<p>It <em>wants</em> to be played well. Its resonance guides my fingers to the right position as if there was a small indentation and going to either side of it pushes me back the right direction.</p>

<p>I’m always amazed by the sheer simplicity of the instrument and how, from its simplicity, masterpieces and virtuosos have emerged.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My violin was in the shop for a bit due to a split seam and for needing a bridge adjustment. I got it back today and, after practicing on the loaner instrument, reminded myself why I invested into getting a good instrument.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Abstract Expressionism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/10/my-abstract-expressionism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Abstract Expressionism" /><published>2023-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/10/my-abstract-expressionism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/10/my-abstract-expressionism.html"><![CDATA[<p>There’s been this idea swirling in my head, where I can’t quite see the full shapes just yet. The raw colors are there, but the subject, the meat of the thing still escapes me - like it is some piece of abstract expressionism.</p>

<p>It’s reaching out from my bones.</p>

<p>I feel it during my walks in the city.</p>

<p>With every time I look at my phone.</p>

<p>Every time I wish to both connect and disconnect.</p>

<p>Every time I wish to do something more with my hands, be more human, make use of the fact that I am a product of evolution and be reminded of the fact that the technology we have is not fully evolved for <em>me</em>.</p>

<p>Why can’t using technology be as calming as breathing in the fresh air near a still lake?</p>

<p>Why can’t using technology be as comforting as eating the first warm bowl of soup when you have a cold?</p>

<p>Why can’t using technology be as uplifting like getting hit by the first rays of sun in Spring?</p>

<p>Why has it become that I need to <em>escape</em> from technology? Did we ever need to escape from hammers, from cars, from refrigerators?</p>

<p>I’m frustrated.</p>

<p>But I feel like the painting is becoming clearer every day with each new brushstroke.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s been this idea swirling in my head, where I can’t quite see the full shapes just yet. The raw colors are there, but the subject, the meat of the thing still escapes me - like it is some piece of abstract expressionism.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vanity Metrics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/09/vanity-metrics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vanity Metrics" /><published>2023-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/09/vanity-metrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/09/vanity-metrics.html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I added some analytics to this blog, since I was already adding some to my project,<a href="/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs.html">Indie Comp Jobs</a>.</p>

<p>But then I realized something: I really don’t care about analytics for my blog. I mean, what do I really get out of it? Seeing how many people are reading? Seeing what they like? I’m not writing for them - I’m writing for me.</p>

<p>I’ll add an email in case there is someone out there that actually does ready these posts and wants to chat, but other than that, I swiftly deleted the analytics because fuck metrics.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday I added some analytics to this blog, since I was already adding some to my project,Indie Comp Jobs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Use Your Advantages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/08/use-your-advantages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Your Advantages" /><published>2023-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/08/use-your-advantages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/08/use-your-advantages.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I have been learning violin for a bit more than 2 years now. I’ve purchased myself a respectable violin and bow, have weekly tutor sessions, and try to practice as often as I can (daily if possible).</p>

<p>Somehow, the teachings in my lessons always seem to translate to more than just the violin. Quite frequently, my teacher tells me to relax, sometimes forcing me to put the violin down and shake out the day from my arms. “You’re stiff, so you tense up, and your playing shows it.” I’ve taken this lesson to other aspects of my life, for example when I try to force things when I know they just aren’t working or becoming stressed over small ideas.</p>

<p>Today I had another lesson.</p>

<p>On the violin, sometimes you need to switch between strings with the same finger, for example, playing D and going down to G, I can use my third finger and roll it from one string to another without picking it up. In this piece, I needed to do something similar, but my tutor said that I should use the “pudginess” of my fingers to my advantage: they can touch both strings at the same time with almost no effort. It shouldn’t always be done like that, but in this case it was advantageous.</p>

<p>I immediately began to think about what other sorts of advantages do I possess in life and how can I best utilize them to improve my life and help others. In hindsight, using the “pudginess” of my fingers to touch both strings is obvious, but not at the moment. So too would be the advantages I discover now that I am actively thinking of them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, I have been learning violin for a bit more than 2 years now. I’ve purchased myself a respectable violin and bow, have weekly tutor sessions, and try to practice as often as I can (daily if possible).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blips</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/07/blips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blips" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/07/blips</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/07/blips.html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so the date is a <em>bit</em> of a lie on this post. It is technically the morning of January 8th - but what even is time, really? Go a couple light-hours away (maybe to Neptune or Pluto) and it’ll still be January 7th in the observer’s eyes. As they say “it’s January 7th somewhere”.</p>

<p>Anyways, I got caught up in the day and slipped a bit on posting for he first time - a blip.</p>

<p>The thing about blips for me is that they, most of the time, result in me completely abandoning the thing I have been doing for weeks, in this case blogging. But this is the first time that I really took notice of this pattern. And here I am, doing it again. It was a blip. And that’s okay. I think I need to be a bit more forgiving of myself for these blips.</p>

<p>To blip is human; to forgive, divine<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/An_Essay_on_Criticism">.</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so the date is a bit of a lie on this post. It is technically the morning of January 8th - but what even is time, really? Go a couple light-hours away (maybe to Neptune or Pluto) and it’ll still be January 7th in the observer’s eyes. As they say “it’s January 7th somewhere”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sick, Inside, and Taking it Easy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/06/sick-inside-and-taking-it-easy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sick, Inside, and Taking it Easy" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/06/sick-inside-and-taking-it-easy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/06/sick-inside-and-taking-it-easy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a bit of a blah day.</p>

<p>A day I woke up sick, checked myself for covid (negative), and proceeded to just lounge about for a while working on <a href="/projects/2023/01/02/indie-comp-jobs.html">Indie Comp Jobs</a>.</p>

<p>Lots of cough drops.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was a bit of a blah day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing Improvement</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/05/writing-improvement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing Improvement" /><published>2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/05/writing-improvement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/05/writing-improvement.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is the 17th day in a row that I have written something and placed it out into the world, regardless if someone is reading it.</p>

<p>And I have to say, that I feel like my voice is starting to really come through in my writing; I am becoming bolder, making the words flow a bit nicer, and developing a tone of my own.</p>

<p>As I have been writing more, I’ve noticed a few new traits I exhibit:</p>
<ul>
  <li>I like to write things in threes. There’s a certain completeness of threes, a rhythm, a “hey those two previous things were nice, but here’s an excellent number 3.” I dunno, just going to go with it - it seems natural.</li>
  <li>Hyphens are my way, and I suppose a lot of people’s way, of just getting to the point of the sentence. No more long winded essays - I just get to the point. Just like that. They’re snappy and immediate.</li>
  <li>Here’s a third bullet. See bullet 1.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today is the 17th day in a row that I have written something and placed it out into the world, regardless if someone is reading it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Barley Tea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/04/barley-tea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Barley Tea" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/04/barley-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/04/barley-tea.html"><![CDATA[<p>Barley tea has been a relatively new discovery for myself. It is exactly what it sounds like: barley boiled in hot water.</p>

<p>But I find myself basically chugging it now.</p>

<p>That slight bit of toasty, warm-by-the-fire, safe-in-my-little-cottage flavor seems to keep calling me back - and it isn’t even that strong of a flavor. It just whispers to me and draws me in for another sip.</p>

<p>I want to make more things like barley tea; things that keep calling me back with their simplicity and always provide just the right amount of delight.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barley tea has been a relatively new discovery for myself. It is exactly what it sounds like: barley boiled in hot water.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lentil Soup Entropy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/03/lentil-soup-entropy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lentil Soup Entropy" /><published>2023-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/03/lentil-soup-entropy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/03/lentil-soup-entropy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I made some delicious lentil soup. I added a bit of heavy cream into it and watched the vortices within the soup as I moved my ladle through it. It made me think back to the show<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt8134186/">Devs</a> and what it would take to simulate such entropy. There must be millions of people making soup a day, all with their own little vortices. How many FLOPS would it take to reverse everyone’s soup that day? I feel like we are not even close to the computing power to simulate that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I made some delicious lentil soup. I added a bit of heavy cream into it and watched the vortices within the soup as I moved my ladle through it. It made me think back to the showDevs and what it would take to simulate such entropy. There must be millions of people making soup a day, all with their own little vortices. How many FLOPS would it take to reverse everyone’s soup that day? I feel like we are not even close to the computing power to simulate that.]]></summary></entry></feed>